<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-06T10:28:18-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">February WAI_? Review: Arrow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/February-WAI" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="February WAI_? Review&amp;#58;  Arrow" /><published>2020-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/February-WAI</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/February-WAI">&lt;!-- readmore --&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">January WAI_? Review: CW’s Crisis On Infinite Earths</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/January-WAI" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="January WAI_? Review&amp;#58;  CW's Crisis On Infinite Earths" /><published>2020-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/January-WAI</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/January-WAI">&lt;p&gt;This month on WAI_? that’s totally not 10+ days late, I listeneded to a bunch of podcasts. Started reading The Mighty Thor, A Flash Miniseries, and watched some shows. But the one big thing that I’m going to talk about this week is CW’s Crisis On Infinite Earths. Crisis (as I will refer to it henceforth) is the name of this year’s annual crossover between the shows that exist in the Arrowverse. Previous crossovers included Flash vs. Arrow, Heroes Join Forces, Invasion!, and Crisis on Earth X. But this year, Crisis On Infinite Earths, step the game up to a whole new level that I didn’t even know existed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- readmore --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crisis felt like a fever dream. Crisis to the Arrowverse to me felt like Endgame was to the MCU. It was the epitome of comic book crossover. It hit all the points that you would expect except for the fact that a show didn’t spin off directly from the crossover event like Legends of Tomorrow did. Some could argue that Green Arrow &amp;amp; The Canaries could count as a spin-off but since it starts after the finale of Arrow I’m not counting it in my books. But nonetheless Crisis pleasantly took me by surprise and I enjoyed it very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crisis was teased a whole god damn year earlier at the end of Elseworlds, which sucked at the time because that meant I had to wait a whole year to see what was going to happen next. The superheroes, in their respective shows would continue their own personal galavants, while the viewer probably forgot about the fact that Novu will be back for the next crossover event. Each show’s season finale roles around and suddenly there he is, pulling you out of the celebration that is the end of the season as each show’s hero(s) celebrates their win over that season’s bad guy. It felt really jarring whenever the show would non-chalantly cut to Novu standing in the crowd or at the doorway, reminding our heros of the upcoming Crisis. It definitely cut the season’s celebrations short as our heros are now reminded that even though it’s over.. it’s not over. I didn’t mind the jarring ending of each season but I definitely didn’t like how they were immediately worrying about the next threat just as the season ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Crisis finally came, it felt something like a D&amp;amp;D session. The Monitor (Novu), somehow aware of how the future should occur, would teleport around and assemble our heroes willy nilly, brought people back to life, gave people their powers back and was able to time travel and do as he pleases to move the plot forward. This was probably the biggest gripe I had while watching Crisis. It didn’t feel as organic as other crossover events but I don’t necessarily think it’s a bad thing. It definitely had an authentic comic book feel to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then came the cameos, which I think was where all the budget for the crossover event went, because there was a lot of big names that cameo’d throughout the five episodes. Most notable ones were Ezra Miller’s DCEU Flash, which was a very pleasant surprise and something fans (as well as myself) wanted to see since the conception of both versions of the Flash. Johnn Wesley Shipp, who plays multiple characters in the show, returned as his role of 1990’s Barry Allen, making that show canon in the universe. Additionally, Smalleville’s Clark Kent was also present, as well as other DC shows that were never mentioned to be canon but now are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was apparent since Elseworlds that Oliver Queen as Arrow would be the main focus of Crisis, as it was teased since Crisis was announced, as well as played the major plot point for Arrow’s final season. Novu prophesized the Green Arrow’s death as he saved the universe. Seeing as it was announced that it was going to be Arrow’s final season, it was expected that Arrow would go out in a blaze of glory as he fought to save the universe. Did those expectations get met? Yes and no. DCTV’s crossover events are infamous for their parking lot fight scenes as our assembled heros fight countless unnamed CGI goonies and call it the Act III conflict and Crisis is no different. The first thing is that Arrow doesn’t even die on this home earth. He dies saving the the citizens of Earth-38, Supergirl’s earth. The second thing is he dies fighting a bunch of (you guessed it) unnamed CGI goonies. And the final nail on the coffin is it cuts away just as the fighting starts rolling and he gets teleported to the ship all battered and bruised and dies shortly thereafter. In my opinion that’s pretty anticlimactic for the titular character who launched the franchise to go. But Oliver Queen’s story isn’t over yet. This is a comic book universe after all, there is always an afterlife, and unsurprisingly, this isn’t the first time Oliver Queen has died. Even though his death is surprisingly the first episode in the crossover, he is still around in the subsequent episodes as some of the heros travel to the afterlife to try and bring back his soul to his body. This is where he gets revived as the Spectre. A powerful being that is meant to stop the protagonist of the whole event. This got my excited because now I get to see Oliver Queen in his final epic confrontational battle before he finally &lt;i&gt;actually&lt;i&gt; dies. But those expectations fall flat a second time. I was hoping for an epic fight sequence that Arrow is best at, mixed with extra magical powers that Spectre now has, but all I got 2-minute “fight” scene with okay CGI as the hero and villian embrace each other and stare into each others eyes in a mix between the final battle between Harry Potter and Voldemort with the purple swirlys at the end of Guardians of the Galaxy where they use the Power Stone. The “fight” ends in an explosion and Spectre’s second (this time real) death. Storywise the implications of this are far reaching as it reboots the universe and changes history and all that kind of comic booky stuff. But the fight itself? 5/10.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the rebooted universe is a fun treat. Flash, Supergirl, and Batwoman are now all on the same earth. Historys have been rewritten and it gives the writers a tool to fix any problems they may have written themselves into in previous seasons. I’m excited to see wehre it goes and welcome the new Universe with open arms. It’ll be interesting to see what the new world without Oliver Queen will be.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">This month on WAI_? that’s totally not 10+ days late, I listeneded to a bunch of podcasts. Started reading The Mighty Thor, A Flash Miniseries, and watched some shows. But the one big thing that I’m going to talk about this week is CW’s Crisis On Infinite Earths. Crisis (as I will refer to it henceforth) is the name of this year’s annual crossover between the shows that exist in the Arrowverse. Previous crossovers included Flash vs. Arrow, Heroes Join Forces, Invasion!, and Crisis on Earth X. But this year, Crisis On Infinite Earths, step the game up to a whole new level that I didn’t even know existed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CASPR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/hi-class" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CASPR" /><published>2020-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/hi-class</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/hi-class">&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! I hope you like our presentation!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">Hi everyone! I hope you like our presentation!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/new-year" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year" /><published>2020-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/new-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/new-year">&lt;p&gt;Okay so it’s finally the new year. I’ve been preparing for the new year for the last little while now. This website/blog thing has been one of the main results to come of it. I thought the new year would be a good place to start journaling, recording my recent happenings and giving me a way of looking back and reflecting the things that I want to reflect on later down the road. Not to mention it’s also been a dream of mine to start a website (and by extension a blog) and I’ve tried numerous times in the past, all of which didn’t end up well, mostly because of the knowledge which resulted in doing things very tediously and in the end made it a lot of work to upkeep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess now that it’s the new year should start it off by listing off a bunch of goals and things that I want to accomplish. Okay let’s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- readmore --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; JohnRivada.Me &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve mentioned it before but now is the time to go into detail about it. My goal with the website is to journal my happenings because I read somewhere some time ago that journaling is good for you and what better way to kill two birds with one stone than by knocking off the ‘make a website’ entry as well and turning the project into a blog. I also plan to add ‘About Me’ and ‘Academic’ sections as well, and make this my &lt;i&gt;sort of&lt;/i&gt; main online presence. Additionally all this journaling and websiting will most definitely help me in my writing which is something that I want to improve upon. One aspect of my site that is already live is the WAI_? section which is something I look forward to filling out as the year goes on. Long story short (because I will probably touch upon it below) is that it will keep track of the entertainment (podcast, music, anime, games, etc.) that I consume and the plan is to write about them on a monthly basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; Todoist &amp;amp; GTD &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GTD, or Getting Things Done is an organization framework that I read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamberg.no/gtd/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and its something that I’ve been slowly trying to work towards for the better part of the last two years. I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://todoist.com/overview&quot;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt; as my main way of keeping track of my To Do Lists and have used it for a good amount before stumbling upon the GTD method and so now I’ve been massaging and reformatting my list and projects to resemble something similar to the GTD method and I’ve lately found a system that works well for me. The goal for the year is to maintain this productivity setup and maybe even refine and improve upon it as time goes around. It has proven pretty useful the last couple months, but it can definitely be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; General Lifestyle Goals &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one that almost everyone has at every new year. Getting active (and then staying active), less junk food, etc. etc. The big ones for me include getting active, less junk food, a better sleep schedule, and getting my finances in order. I’ve been meaning to get active, either by going for morning runs or by going to the gym with my girlfriend on campus. I’m not trying to lose weight or anything, mostly just stay in shape and stay healthy. Less junk food… I’d like to thank university for that one. Thanks to the time and stress burdens it has given me I’ve gotten into the habit of wanting to just simply order food (mostly McDonalds or Thai Express) instead of eating something I make at home. The amount of soft drinks I consume has also increased and it is admittedly at a level that I enjoy at the moment but don’t when looking back. The plan is to monitor how much I drink and even times I crave a drink and try and reduce it to a better number. Similiar to the junk foods. I’m going to try to limit it to around once a week (or even once every two weeks if I can).  The financial affairs is something of a personally set goal for myself. I’m by no means in any financial trouble (though I’m not super financially set either. If I were on the spectrum of poor to rich out of my mind I’d be hovering near the middle but leaning more towards the poorer side). At the time of writing I’ve got ~$700 in my chequing account, ~$1000 in my savings account, ~$12,000 in my TFSA and $69 (nice) on my credit card bill. I’ve got a lot of holiday bills that I’ve got to sort out so a good chunk of it might going to different accounts but the idea is there. Based off the 50/30/20 (Of my paychecks, the money is allotted 50% to savings, 30% to living, and 20% to whatever I want) budget I started 2 years ago, I’m currently in a deficit where I have overspent by ~$2,700. So on the topic of finances, one goal of mine is to take ~$200 off each paycheck and put it towards this ‘personal debt’ I have acquired. Additionally I want to look back at the spending I did in 2019 and find spots where I could limit spending and thus save money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; Backlogs &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay so this is where WAI_? comes into play. There’s &lt;b&gt;a lot&lt;/b&gt; of games that I bought and haven’t played or media that I started/want to start and haven’t finished. I’ve got all my PS4, Switch and PC games that I bought and want to play. Additionally (but not as importantly) I also have games on my 3DS, PSP, PSVita and PS3 that I bought and want to finish. It’s a huge backlog and so one goal I have for the year is to finish with more games finished than played. A big task but it’s probably doable. I’ve also got a list of podcasts that I enjoy and want to catch up on. And the same can be said for anime. manga, books, TV shows, and movies. I definitely want to play/read/listen to at least a good chunk of it for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lumeray, a D&amp;amp;D setting I created has been the child of my players whoms’t I appreciate so so much and myself from playing D&amp;amp;D the last two years. They started from level 1 and are currently at level 9, with the third season coming starting up in May. There have been 3 core players with 2 players that left due to moving out of the city. It is something that I want to develop, flesh out, and be really proud of (not to say that I’m not already proud of it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt; Hobbies &amp;amp; Other Things &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading more is definitely something I want to do. Continue my school is another thing, and maybe pick up a couple hobbies here and there. But those are low on the list and I haven’t put as much thought into them as I did the others.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="site" /><summary type="html">Okay so it’s finally the new year. I’ve been preparing for the new year for the last little while now. This website/blog thing has been one of the main results to come of it. I thought the new year would be a good place to start journaling, recording my recent happenings and giving me a way of looking back and reflecting the things that I want to reflect on later down the road. Not to mention it’s also been a dream of mine to start a website (and by extension a blog) and I’ve tried numerous times in the past, all of which didn’t end up well, mostly because of the knowledge which resulted in doing things very tediously and in the end made it a lot of work to upkeep. I guess now that it’s the new year should start it off by listing off a bunch of goals and things that I want to accomplish. Okay let’s get to it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Elias</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/elias" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elias" /><published>2019-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/elias</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/elias">&lt;p&gt;Elias. Yes. That will be you. You reading this. Your name will be Elias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem with writing these blog posts is never knowing &lt;i&gt; who &lt;/i&gt; I’m writing for. So here we are. I am designating you, the reader as Elias. This will give me a person, a one man audience, to write to, to give me a direction for all these posts. Why Elias? I don’t know. It was just the first name to show up in my head. Elias is a name of an NPC in my D&amp;amp;D setting so it’llb e a little weird because at times it’ll feel like I’m writing to a fictional fantasy character but who knows maybe that’ll be easier… or maybe it won’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay thanks Elias!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Elias. Yes. That will be you. You reading this. Your name will be Elias. The biggest problem with writing these blog posts is never knowing who I’m writing for. So here we are. I am designating you, the reader as Elias. This will give me a person, a one man audience, to write to, to give me a direction for all these posts. Why Elias? I don’t know. It was just the first name to show up in my head. Elias is a name of an NPC in my D&amp;amp;D setting so it’llb e a little weird because at times it’ll feel like I’m writing to a fictional fantasy character but who knows maybe that’ll be easier… or maybe it won’t. Okay thanks Elias!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">But Why</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/but-why" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="But Why" /><published>2019-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/but-why</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/but-why">&lt;p&gt;Well here it is. This is what it’s all been leading towards. This right here. My blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to start journaling for a year or two now and I’ve wanted to start a website for much longer. So I guess the best thing was to check both off my To Do List and start a blog. I’ve gotten a free domain name thanks to my school e-mail, and I think it’s only free for a year it’s okay. A year’s longer than nothing. It’ll at least let me try out this whole blogging ordeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why blog? At first it was just a hobby that I’ve wanted to pick up (journaling that is). But these days it serves a higher purpose. Its so curb my anxiety. I’ve been told that journaling and writing about my anxiety will help me manage it and managing it is super high up on my To Do List these days. So that’s kind of been the main motivation of getting this blog set up, as a means of journaling my anxiety whilst satisfying my desire to start a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- readmore --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem and will always be the biggest problem however is finding the time to write a blog post that completely captures everything that I am thinking at that moment in time. School has been so busy lately and as I lie in bed writing this out I’m dreading my midterm tomorrow that I didn’t study for all weekend because I was at a conference. It doesn’t seem like it will be a hard midterm (it’s Natural Products Biosynthesis… easy right?) but at the same time the lack of studying has been fueling my recent anxiety. It’s been such a long two weeks that I think one this midterm ends tomorrow I’ll feel like a free man as I get to not worry about the exam for a good amount of weeks. Maybe I’ll be able to actually get some work one in the lab or spend some time cleaning it up sincec it has not been tended to for a couple of months now (that’s a a blog post in and of itself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anxiety right now is managed. I’m not feeling much in the chest but I feel like it’s not far around the corner and sooner rather than later things are gonna hit the fun, but so far everything seems okay which is a really good sign. Tomorrow marks the beginning of some catch up and I’m really excited, I’ve neglected my To Do List for the last week or so and its starting to get unruly but hey such is life right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made a grave mistake writing in my bed as I seem to be falling asleep while writing which means ending. Which is what this is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Well here it is. This is what it’s all been leading towards. This right here. My blog. I’ve been wanting to start journaling for a year or two now and I’ve wanted to start a website for much longer. So I guess the best thing was to check both off my To Do List and start a blog. I’ve gotten a free domain name thanks to my school e-mail, and I think it’s only free for a year it’s okay. A year’s longer than nothing. It’ll at least let me try out this whole blogging ordeal. So why blog? At first it was just a hobby that I’ve wanted to pick up (journaling that is). But these days it serves a higher purpose. Its so curb my anxiety. I’ve been told that journaling and writing about my anxiety will help me manage it and managing it is super high up on my To Do List these days. So that’s kind of been the main motivation of getting this blog set up, as a means of journaling my anxiety whilst satisfying my desire to start a website.</summary></entry></feed>